Newton, Mass. First Church records, 1664-1974.
Congregational Library & Archives
Newton, Mass. First Church records, 1664-1974.
RG0132
Congregational Library & Archives
20.57 Cubic Feet
(25 boxes)
The land encompassing today's Newton was first settled by English colonizers in 1630 as part of "the newe towne." In 1681, Cambridge Village was incorporated as a separate town from Cambridge and in 1691 the town was renamed Newtown. The town name was changed yet again in 1766 to Newton. The first meeting house was built in 1660. John Elliot Jr. was installed as the first pastor. The second meeting house was constructed in 1698. In 1720, and again in 1770, the homes of John Cotton and later Jonas Meriam were destroyed by fire and with them the earliest records of the church. The third meeting house was built in 1721 with subsequent meeting houses constructed in 1805, 1847, and 1904. In 1764, a group of parishioners in the western part of Newton built their own meeting house to hold Sunday services, and in 1781 they formally gathered the West Parish Church. In 1972 the First Church in Newton dissolved after more than three hundred years of service to the Newton community. This collection contains the administrative records of the First Church in Newton, Massachusetts, as well as the records of the members and ministers of the church.
Appleton, Nathaniel, 1693-1784
Boynton, M. Russell (Morrison Russell), 1887-1953
Bradley, Dwight J. (Dwight Jaques), 1889-1957
First Congregational Church (Newton, Mass.)
Furber, Daniel Little, 1820-1899
Guptill, Nathanael M. (Nathanael Mann), 1917-2007
Holmes, Theodore J.
Homer, Jonathan, 1759-1843
Noyes, Edward MacArthur, 1858-
Stocking, Jay T. (Jay Thomas), 1870-1936
Weiskel, Frank M., -1996
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Initial collection was donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by the First Congregational Church in Newton, Massachusetts, in 1972 following the dissolution of the church; no accession number.
An additional accession of a photograph album was added to the collection in 2013; no accession number.
A folder of papers from Samuel Back were transferred to this collection from the The Congregational Christian Church and the Evangelical and Reformed Church Merger Collection (RG5387); 2019-18.
A Cookbook from the Women's Benevolent Society was donated to the Congregational Library & Archives by Myra Dodick in July 2019; 2019-21.
Digital Copies
Records within this collection were digitized as part of the New England's Hidden Histories project. Digital reproductions may be accessed online through our digital archive.
Accruals
Additional accruals are expected for this collection in the form of full-text transcription. There is no anticipated date for this accrual.
Historical Note
The land encompassing today's Newton was first settled by English colonizers in 1630 as part of "the newe towne," though the lands of this new town were within the traditional tribal lands of the Massachusett peoples. The "newe towne" was renamed to Cambridge in 1638. In 1646 the missionary John Eliot and a small band of Native Americans lead by Waban settled the village of Nonantum, from the Algonquian term for rejoicing, in an area of Cambridge that would be today's Newton. Nonantum became the first of John Eliot's "praying Indian villages." However, five years later, Eliot and Waban were forced to relocate the village and its people to present day Natick due to the insatiable land hunger of the colonists in nearby Cambridge and Boston. In 1681, Cambridge Village was incorporated as a separate town from Cambridge and in 1691 the town was renamed Newtown. The town name was changed yet again in 1766 to Newton.
The first meeting house, built on the site of today's Old Burying Ground, in Newton was built in 1660 by parishioners who had tired of making the trip to Cambridge proper for Sunday worship. In 1664 the Massachusetts General Court granted the parishioners of this area leave to form their own church, the First Congregational Church. That same year John Elliot Jr. was installed as the first pastor of the newly gathered church. The second meeting house was constructed in 1698 across the street from the first meeting house. In 1720, and again in 1770, the homes of John Cotton and later Jonas Meriam were destroyed by fire and with them the earliest records of the church.
In 1721, the church was ordered by the General Court to move their building; that same year saw the construction of the third meeting house and all subsequent meeting houses would be built on the same land. In 1764, a group of parishioners in the western part of Newton built their own meeting house to hold Sunday services, and in 1781 they formally gathered the West Parish Church. The fourth meeting house was constructed in 1805. The Federal Street Church in Boston gifted First Church its first bell in 1810. The first Sunday school was established in 1816. The fifth meeting house was constructed in 1847.
In 1895, the church and parish organizations incorporated as a single organization. The sixth, and final, meeting house was constructed in 1904. During the 1940s the First Church contemplated the formation of a federated church with the First Baptist Church in Newton, but did not follow through. In 1972 the First Church in Newton dissolved after more than three hundred years of service to the Newton community.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the administrative records of the First Church in Newton, Massachusetts, as well as the records of the members and ministers of the church. The collection includes church meeting minutes, financial records for the church and building, papers and sermons from ministers, church bulletins and calendars, vital membership records, scrapbooks, diaries, programs, and photographic materials.
Arrangement
This collection has been arranged into the six topical series listed below. Some of those series contain topical sub-series which are also listed below. Within each series materials are arranged in chronological order. When appropriate, closely related and/or continuous materials have been arranged together.
Series 1: Church records, 1773-1972
Series 2: Membership records, 1664-1973
Sub-series 1: Registers and directories, 1664-1973
Sub-series 2: Admissions, dismissions, and membership records, 1869-1969
Sub-series 3: Vital records, 1904-1967
Series 3: Financial records, 1708-1974
Sub-series 1: Church finances, 1708-1968
Sub-series 2: Building records, 1785-1974
Sub-series 3: Pew records, 1805-1902
Series 4: Auxiliary groups, 1854-1974
Sub-series 1: Sunday School, 1854-1924
Sub-series 2: Women's Benevolent and Church Aid Society, 1861-1974
Sub-series 3: Benevolence Committee, 1870-1954
Sub-series 4: Little People's Mission, 1876-1881
Sub-series 5: Furber Circle, 1883-1967
Sub-series 6: Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1887-1916
Sub-series 7: Ladies Foreign Missionary Society, 1887-1918
Sub-series 8: Ladies Furnishing Committee, 1903-1906
Sub-series 9: Kelsey Circle, 1938-1967
Sub-series 10: The Men's Club, 1939-1959
Sub-series 11: Friendly Service Committee, 1939-1972
Sub-series 12: Reading Committee, 1946-1960
Series 5: Ministerial papers, 1741-1967
Sub-series 1: Nathanael Appleton, 1741
Sub-series 2: Jonathan Homer, 1763-1839
Sub-series 3: Daniel L. Furber, 1824-1899
Sub-series 4: Theodore J. Holmes, 1883-1893
Sub-series 5: Edward M. Noyes, 1889-1941
Sub-series 6: Jay T. Stocking, 1923-1936
Sub-series 7: Dwight J. Bradley, 1928-1933
Sub-series 8: Morrison Russell Boynton, 1936-1954
Sub-series 9: Nathanael M. Guptill, 1953-1958
Sub-series 10: Frank M. Weiskel, 1958-1967
Series 6: Publications, 1841-1971
Technical Requirements
To access digital materials on our digital archive, it is strongly recommended that you use the latest available version of Microsoft Edge, Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, or Safari (Apple).
Baptismal records.; Church buildings.; Church bulletins.; Church correspondence.; Church finance.; Church membership.; Church records and registers.; Church societies.; Clergy -- Correspondence.; Diaries.; Fraternal organizations.; Marriage records.; Necrologies.; New England's Hidden Histories.; Pews and pew rights.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sermons, American.; Sermons, American -- Early works to 1800.; Sunday schools.; Travel writing.; First Baptist Church in Newton (Newton Center, Newton, Mass.); First Congregational Church (Newton, Mass.); Newton (Mass.) -- Church history.
- Church records, 1773 1972; 1773-1972; 62 Folders; 15 Volumes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains records related to the administration of the church and includes meeting minutes, annual reports, clerk's records, church correspondence, photographs, and anniversary-related records.
  - Church records, 1773 1827; 1773-1827 (Box 2, Volume 1)
  - Church records, 1827 1831; 1827-1831 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Church records, 1827 1873; 1827-1873 (Box 2, Volume 2)
  - Church records, 1873 1891; 1873-1891 (Box 2, Volume 3)
  - Church records, 1892 1910; 1892-1910 (Box 3, Volume 2)
  - Church records, 1910 1931; 1910-1931 (Box 4, Volume 2)
  - Miscellaneous church records, 1783 1869; 1783-1869 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Covenant and confessions of faith, 1830 1835; 1830, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Confession of faith and covenant signers, 1859 1895; 1859-1895 (Box 5, Volume 1)
  - Church manuals, 1859 1952; 1859-1952 (Box 24)
  - Pastoral committee minutes and correspondence, 1859 1966; 1859-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pastoral committee minutes, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pastoral committee minutes, 1953 1954; 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Standing committee records, 1884 1888; 1884-1888 (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Standing committee records, 1888 1895; 1888-1895 (Box 5, Volume 2)
  - Standing committee records, 1895 1929; 1895-1929 (Box 3, Volume 1)
  - Standing committee minutes, 1929 1931; 1929-1931 (Box 2, Volume 4)
  - Committee on pastorate records, 1893 1894; 1893-1894 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Candidates for pastorate, 1893 1894; 1893-1894 (Box 1, Volume 3)
  - Edward M. Noyes church records, 1894 1895; 1894-1895 (Box 22, Volume 4)
  - By-laws, 1895 1956; 1895-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Prudential committee records, 1895 1931; 1895-1931 (Box 4, Volume 1)
  - Annual reports, 1898 1900; 1898-1900 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Annual reports, 1901 1902; 1901-1902 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual reports, 1903 1904; 1903-1904 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Annual reports, 1905 1908; 1905-1908 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Annual reports, 1909 1912; 1909-1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Annual reports, 1913 1916; 1913-1916 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1916 1920; 1916-1920 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports, 1920 1924; 1920-1924 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports, 1927 1928; 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual reports, 1928 1929; 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annual reports, 1930 1932; 1930-1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports, 1933 1937; 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Annual reports, 1937 1941; 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual reports, 1952 1954; 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual reports, 1955 1959; 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual reports, 1960 1964; 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual reports, 1965 1969; 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annual reports, 1970 1971; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Missions and missionary correspondence, 1900 1967; 1900-1967 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Missions and missionary correspondence, 1901 1927; 1901, 1925-1927 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Missions and missionary correspondence, 1937 1958; 1937-1958 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - 240th anniversary dedication of new building, 1903 1904; 1903-1904 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Communion silver at the MFA, 1911 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - 250th anniversary committee record book, 1912 1914; 1912-1914 (Box 18, Volume 1)
  - 250th anniversary programs and clippings, 1914 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Clerk's records, 1932 1935; 1932-1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clerk's records, 1936 1938; 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clerk's records, 1940 1942; 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clerk's records, 1943 1945; 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clerk's records, 1946 1948; 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clerk's records, 1949 1951; 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clerk's records, 1952 1955; 1952-1955 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Clerk's records, 1956 1960; 1956-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clerk's records, 1961 1964; 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clerk's records, 1965 1968; 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - 275th anniversary, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - 275th anniversary historical addresses and correspondence, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - 275th anniversary programs and clippings, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - 275th anniversary preaching mission and correspondence, 1939 1940; 1939-1940 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Newton Baptist Church merger records, 1945 1969; 1945-1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Diaconate board minutes, 1961 1964; 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Diaconate board minutes, 1965 1969; 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 300th anniversary committee minutes and correspondence, 1962 1964; 1962-1964 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - 300th anniversary, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - 300th anniversary addresses, 1964 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - 300th anniversary photographs, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - 300th anniversary photographs, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Samuel H. Back correspondence, 1964 1966; 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Final service records, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Final service clippings, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Final service program and annotated photographic printouts, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Last service photographs, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Postcards, circa 1972 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Communion silver and monument photographs, circa 1972 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Choir photographs, undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Membership records, 1664 1973; 1664-1973; 56 Folders; 11 Volumes
  This series, which contains three sub-series, contains records relating to the members of the First Church and includes vital records, such as baptismal and marriage records, records of admissions and dismissions, records relating to members, and member registers.
  - Registers and directories, 1664 1973; 1664-1973; 4 Folders; 9 Volumes
    This sub-series contains registers, lists of members, and membership indexes.
    - Register, 1664 1973; 1664-1973 (Box 25)
    - Register, 1773 1867; 1773-1867 (Box 8, Volume 1)
    - Absences, 1834 1841; 1834-1841 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Register, 1835 1838; 1835-1838 (Box 5, Volume 3)
    - Register, 1876 1891; 1876-1891 (Box 5, Volume 4)
    - Member directory, 1885 (Box 5, Volume 5)
    - Annual roll call, 1890 1891; 1890-1891 (Box 5, Volume 6)
    - Membership lists, 1895 1923; 1895-1923 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Signatures of members, 1895 1971; 1895-1971 (Box 5, Volume 7)
    - Index of membership, 1900 1930; circa 1900-1930 (Box 8, Volume 2)
    - Attendance records, 1902 1957; 1902-1957 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Member directories, 1923 1953; 1923-1924, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Register, 1957 1973; 1957-1973 (Box 5, Volume 8)
    - Alphabetical index to chronological membership list, undated (Box 8, Volume 3)
  - Admissions, dismissions, and membership records, 1869 1969; 1869-1969; 42 Folders; 2 Volumes
    This sub-series contains records of admissions and dismissions as well as records relating to the membership and makeup of the First Church and includes photograph albums, membership records, applications and transfer documents, and correspondence.
    - Membership certificates, 1869 1902; 1869-1902 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Membership certificates, 1921 1928; 1921-1928 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Membership certificates, 1950 1952; 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Paul Family album, circa 1870 (Box 22, Volume 2)
    - Paul Family album, circa 1870 (Box 22, Volume 3)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1871 1902; 1871-1902 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1871 1903; 1871-1903 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1872 1902; 1872-1902 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1878 1902; 1878-1902 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1884 1903; 1884-1903 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1910 1965; 1910-1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1926 1949; 1926-1949 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1926 1952; 1926-1952 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1932 1950; 1932-1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Admissions and dismissions, 1950 1965; 1950-1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Dismissions: correspondence, 1887 1891; 1887-1891 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Member applications, 1912 1918; 1912-1918 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Member applications, 1921 1929; 1921-1929 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - War of 1812 and Spanish-American War veterans, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Rawlinson family photographs, 1920 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - World War II scrapbook, 1942 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - World War II scrapbook, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - World War II scrapbook, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - World War II scrapbook, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - World War II scrapbook, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - World War II correspondence, 1942 1943; 1942-1943 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - World War II correspondence, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - World War II correspondence, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - World War II correspondence, 1944 1946; 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - World War II lists, 1945 1947; 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Laity sermons, 1943 1963; 1943-1963 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Active and inactive members, 1950 1969; circa 1950-1969 (Box 9)
    - Inactive members, 1950 1969; circa 1950-1969 (Box 10)
    - Dismissions, 1952 1959; 1952-1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Dismissions, 1959 1971; 1959-1971 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Transfer correspondence and membership certificates, 1953 1954; 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Transfer correspondence and membership certificates, 1955 1959; 1955-1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Transfer correspondence and membership certificates, 1959 1967; 1959-1967 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - David Ralph "Mac" Maclean jubilee, 1959 1963; 1959-1963 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - New member class photographs, 1959 1965; 1959-1965 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Andover-Newton Theological school students, 1962 1965; 1962-1965 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Conscientious objectors, 1964 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Unknown portrait, undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Vital records, 1904 1967; 1904-1967; 10 Volumes
    This collection contains vital records for the members of the First Church and includes baptismal records, marriage records, and records of deaths.
    - Baptismal records, 1904 1929; 1904-1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Memorandum book, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Funeral records, 1923 1966; 1923-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Funeral records, 1926 1967; 1926-1967 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Necrologies, 1930 1937; 1930-1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Deaths: memorandum of data for church records, 1930 1967; 1930-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Beptisms: correspondence, 1934 1954; 1934-1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Funeral services, eulogies, and correspondence, 1937 1965; 1937-1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Marriages: correspondence, 1938 1951; 1938-1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Marriage certificates, 1939 1953; 1939-1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Financial records, 1708 1974; 1708-1974; 54 Folders; 29 Volumes
  This series, which contains three sub-series, contains records relating to the finances of the First and includes records directly relating to finances and financial records, records relating to the maintenance of the church building, and records relating to pews and pew owners.
  - Church finances, 1708 1968; 1708-1968; 24 Folders; 17 Volumes
    This sub-series contains records relating the finances of the First Church and includes bills and receipts, cash books, ledgers and account books, fundraising records, and parish subscriber records.
    - Account book, 1708 1778; 1708-1778 (Box 7, Volume 1)
    - Account book, 1779 1795; 1779-1795 (Box 7, Volume 2)
    - Account book, 1796 1817; 1796-1817 (Box 7, Volume 3)
    - Bills and payments, 1780 1800; 1780-1800 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Bills and payments, 1780 1848; 1780-1848 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Bills and payments, 1800 1805; 1800-1805 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bills and payments, 1801 1814; 1801-1814 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Bills and payments, 1815 1847; 1815-1847 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Bills and payments, 1847 1881; 1847-1881 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bills and payments, 1869 1903; 1869-1903 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Bills and payments, 1882 1897; 1882-1897 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Parish meeting warrants, 1778 1790; 1778-1790 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Parish meeting warrants, 1791 1805; 1791-1805 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Parish meeting warrants, 1806 1855; 1806-1855 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Parish bonds, 1784 1811; 1784-1811 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Edmund Trowbridge receipts, 1786 1804; 1786-1804 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Treasurer's account book, 1795 1846; 1795-1846 (Box 8, Volume 4)
    - Parish assessments, 1779 1834; 1779-1834 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Parish tax releases, 1824 1833; 1824-1833 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Parish tax releases, 1828 1835; 1828-1835 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Parish subscriptions, 1844 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Parish records, 1846 1860; 1846-1860 (Box 11, Volume 1)
    - Cash book, 1862 1874; 1862-1874 (Box 8, Volume 5)
    - Cash journal, 1888 1895; 1888-1895 (Box 7, Volume 10)
    - Cash book, 1896 1907; 1896-1907 (Box 7, Volume 11)
    - Financial records, 1882 1895; 1882-1895 (Box 7, Volume 4)
    - Financial records, 1896 1904; 1896-1904 (Box 7, Volume 5)
    - Financial records, 1905 1909; 1905-1909 (Box 7, Volume 6)
    - Communion collections, 1883 1888; 1883-1888 (Box 7, Volume 7)
    - Contributions, 1895 1897; 1895-1897 (Box 7, Volume 8)
    - Contributions, 1895 1899; 1895-1899 (Box 7, Volume 9)
    - Contributions, 1900 1904; 1900-1904 (Box 8, Volume 6)
    - Bequests, 1912 1964; 1912-1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Endowments and bequests, 1920 1935; 1920-1935 (Box 7, Volume 13)
    - Budgets, 1923 1954; 1923-1954 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Subscribers, 1935 1943; 1935-1943 (Box 7, Volume 14)
    - Canvassing materials, 1938 1959; 1938-1959 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Canvassing photographs, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Prudential committee minutes, 1941 1960; 1941-1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Prudential committee minutes, 1961 1965; 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Prudential committee minutes, 1966 1968; 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Building records, 1785 1974; 1785-1974; 22 Folders; 5 Volumes
    This sub-series contains records related to the upkeep of the physical church and includes deeds, building committee records, photographs of church building interiors and exteriors, and building assessments.
    - Building committee records, 1785 1914; 1785-1914 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Building committee records, 1804 1869; 1804-1806, 1869 (Box 7, Volume 15)
    - Building committee records, 1898 1904; 1898-1904 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Freeholder records, 1778 1805; 1778-1805 (Box 11, Volume 2)
    - Freeholders records, 1806 1846; 1806-1846 (Box 8, Volume 8)
    - Assessments, 1790 1878; 1790-1823, 1878 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Meeting house accounts, 1804 1808; 1804-1808 (Box 12, Volume 1)
    - Deeds, 1804 1817; 1804-1817 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Assessments, 1839 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Deeds, 1870 1890; 1870-1890 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Insurance, 1877 1890; 1877-1890 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Old meeting house" illustration, 1889 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Deeds, 1890 1932; 1890-1932 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Building committee records, 1891 1902; 1891-1902 (Box 7, Folder 16)